Bart McLeroy

Mediator / Arbitrator

bart@mcleroyadr.com 214-763-2577

Profile

Mediator / arbitrator with extensive experience resolving commercial disputes.

Alternative Dispute Resolution Experience

Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

2015 – Present

Arbitrator for securities industry consumer / broker and broker / employer disputes.

Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

2007 - Present

Arbitrator for property valuation disputes between property owners and county appraisal districts.

Texas Department of Insurance

2014 - 2019

Mediator for health insurance carrier / provider billing disputes.

Dallas County Courts

2008 - 2010

Settlement week volunteer mediator for civil district courts.

SquareTrade, Inc.

2003 - 2006

Mediator for eBay buyer / seller disputes. Over 1,000 mediations conducted.

Real Estate Experience

Jones Lang LaSalle

2003 - 2017

Provided outsourced real estate services for multinational clients. Job duties included consulting, sales, leasing, and portfolio / asset management. Worked with office, retail, industrial, land, and telecommunication sites.

Cousins Properties

1999 - 2003

Managed lease administration, forecasting, utility rebilling, \$25M in annual collections, and preparation of annual budget for 1.4 million square foot landmark commercial property.

Teaching Experience

Collin College

2018 - Present

Professor of Real Estate

Tarrant County College

2005 - 2016

Adjunct Professor of Real Estate

Education

University of Applied Sciences (Ludwigshafen, Germany) University of Texas at Arlington University of Illinois MBA, Logistics, 2018 M.S., Real Estate, 2004 B.A., Economics, 1998

Credentials: Texas Real Estate Broker, Texas Property Tax Consultant, Washington Real Estate Managing Broker

ADR Training: See attached

Bart McLeroy ADR Training (Current as of May 4, 2023)

North Lake College (Irving, Texas)

Negotiation Skills for Dispute Resolution (40 hours)

Mediation: A Comprehensive Introduction (40 hours)

Introduction to Dispute Resolution (40 hours)

Introduction to Law (40 hours)

Texas Institute for Public Problem Solving

Conflict Prevention and Management (4 hours)

National Academy of Arbitrators

Arbitration Workshop (2005) (8 hours) Arbitrator Training Workshop (2008)

(8 hours)

Arbitrator Training Workshop (2020)

(8 hours)

Annual Meeting & Education Workshop (2023) (21 hours)

Association for Conflict Resolution

Mediating & Negotiating Collection Cases (1 hour)

<u>University of Texas at Austin School of Law</u> International Arbitration (8.25 hours)

University of Wisconsin – Madison

Mediation Techniques for Managing Conflict (12 hours)

State Bar of Texas

Law of Arbitration (2 hours)

North Seattle College

Alternative Dispute Resolution (50 hours)

University of Texas at Arlington

Advanced ADR for Property Tax Appraisal (8 hours)

<u>Texas Mediator Credentialing Association</u> Mediation Symposium (2017) (6.25 hours)

Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

Arbitrator Training (10 hours)

Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

Basic Arbitrator Training (12 hours) Expungement Training (1.5 hours)

Universiteit Leiden

Arbitration of International Disputes (10 hours)

Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors

Acting as Advocate in Mediation (1 hour) Arbitration - an Introduction (1 hour)

American Bar Association

Arbitration CLE (7.5 hours)
2019 Advanced Mediation Institute

(15 hours)

Texas Realtors

Advanced Mediator Training (6 hours) Ombudsman Training (1.5 hours)

National Association of Railroad Referees

Annual Meeting (2022) (8 hours)